Okay, here we're going to go over the idea of a pendulum.
So, if you think of your upper body as part the pendulum, using these two clubs to keep my club; putting club head on line here.
So, all I want to do is take the club back and you see how it's a pendulum motion.
This way you eliminate a lot of motion in your body and your hands so you can keep the putt on line.
The secret to a good putt; at least getting the right speed and the right line is to keep your club head from moving all over the place.
So, I use these two guide posts so I can keep the club on a pendulum type motion and that will help make my putts that much more accurate.
There's a lot of little tricks in putting because once again these; the putts really count for a lot of strokes in golf even though you may consider it the least athletic of everything you do out here, they count a lot.
So, you've got to find a way to get this nice pendulum motion.
So, you're using your body to putt because you don't want to use your hands when you putt.
You don't swat at it with your hands.
You use the body in somewhat of a pendulum motion.
So, try to get that rhythm and feeling.
You don't even need to have to have a ball.
Just think about being relaxed and moving in a pendulum motion and that will really help your putting motion when it counts.